All right, first-years, introduce yourselves.
（田代(たしろ)秀水(ひでみ)）じゃあ１年生自己紹介
（１年生たち）はい
Yes, sir!
I-I'm Sugawara Koushi from Nagamushi Junior High!
（菅原(すがわら)孝支(こうし)）な長虫(ながむし)中出身
菅原孝支です
I played setter!
セタやてました
Thank you for having me!
よろしくお願いします
I-I'm Azumane Asahi from Seikoudai Junior High!
（東峰(あずまね)旭(あさひ)）せ西光台(せいこうだい)中出身
東峰旭です
I played left wing spiker! Thank you for hafing mwe!
レフトでした
よろしくお願いしゃふす
（菅原）プ
（東峰）かんだ
I messed up.
I'm Sawamura Daichi from Izumitate Junior High!
（澤村(さわむら)大地(だいち)）泉館(いずみだて)中学校出身
澤村大地です
I played left wing spiker!
レフトでした
After seeing Karasuno's match at nationals,
I decided I would come here!
烏野(からすの)が全国行た試合
見てから―
烏野に来るて決めてました
Thank you for having me!
よろしくお願いします
（部員たち）う
Oh, I see. That's great.
（田代）おおそうなのかいいぞ
Let's aim to win at nationals!
（田代）目指せ全国優勝だ
Yes, sir!
（菅原･東峰･澤村）はい
Oh, I'm Tashiro.
（田代）ああ俺は田代だ
一応この部の主将な
I guess you could call me the captain of this team.
All right. I'll stop by again once you guys are done.
（顧問）それじゃあ終わる頃
また来るから
Yes, sir!
（田代）
はいよし練習始めんぞ
All right, let's start practice!
Okay!
（部員たち）うす
Um...
（菅原）あの今の先生
顧問ですよね
That teacher was the advisor, right?
Is there someone else that's more like a coach?
他に監督的な人て
（黒川(くろかわ)広樹(ひろき)）いないぞ
Nope.
That was Kurokawa from Hisa Junior High, right?
今のて
久(ひさ)中の黒川君だよな
Do you know him?
知り合い
Our schools played each other.
中学で当たて攻撃も守備も
すげえうまくて覚えてる
I remember him being really good
at both offense and defense.
ほう
（菅原）マジかすげえ
Seriously? That's awesome.
We finally made it to the Karasuno!
（澤村･東峰･菅原）
来たんだあの烏野に
Episode Six:
The Chemical Change of Encounters
Hey, Kurokawa.
なあ黒川
Tell me the secret behind receiving serves.
サブレシブのコツ教えて
I'm the type that goes right for
the ball once the other team hits it.
俺は相手が打た瞬間に
ガていくタイプです
I see...
（３人）ああ
Clean up!
（田代）片づけ
（部員たち）ういす
Okay!
Hey, even though there's a tournament coming up,
we haven't had many practice matches, have we?
なあ大会近いのに
練習試合少ないよな
They were saying that ever since Coach Ukai left,
we've lost connections with other schools.
烏養(うかい)監督が
いなくなてから―
他校とのつながりも
すげえ減たて言うもんな
Apparently, even the school we regularly had
practice matches with declined the most recent offer.
最近まで定期的にやてた
練習試合の相手にも―
直近の試合断られたて
Why?
え何で
It means we're not worth their precious time.
（黒川）俺たちに貴重な時間を
割く価値がないてことだ
I knew that Karasuno wasn't the same team as before.
（澤村）烏野が前と違うのは
分かていた
けど練習を
頑張てさえいれば―
But I thought that if we kept practicing,
we could turn things around.
また盛り上げていけると
思ていた
It wasn't like the team was fighting,
or that we were in some sort of hopeless situation.
何か大きな波乱や―
絶望的な出来事が
あるわけじゃない
なのに
Yet...
the fear of slowly losing our way encroached.
じわじわと―
道が分からなく
なていくような恐怖
（澤村）あの
（部員たち）ん
Um!
残て練習していても
いいですか
Could I stay behind and practice a little more?!
I'll make sure to lock up!
ちゃんと閉めますので
M-Me too!
お俺もいいすか
Me three!
俺も先生にも
言ておきますから
We'll let the advisor know too!
Sure.
We can't go on like this!
（澤村）このままじゃダメだ
It may seem like there's time, but there isn't!
時間はあるようでないんだ
You totally sound like a teacher!
（菅原）何か先生ぽい
（東峰）澤村君て
ホントに俺たちとタメ
Are you really the same age as us, Sawamura?
ボル拾いでも
できることはある
Even if we only pick up loose balls,
there are still things we can do!
（菅原･東峰）おお
（田代）でい
（黒川）う
Figure out where he's going to hit it from his form!
（澤村）スパイクの
フォムからコスを読む
（黒川）う
（澤村）ぐ
Hey! Why did you catch that?
おい何で取た
あすすみません
I-I'm sorry!
We'll think and act on our own.
（澤村）
自分たちで考え行動する
We'll do everything that we possibly can right now.
今できることを―
精いぱいやる
Starting tomorrow, we have the interhigh prelims.
（顧問）明日から
インタハイ予選です
Let's do our best so that we don't have any regrets.
悔いの残らないよう
頑張りましょう
Right!
（部員たち）はい
Let's aim to win at nationals!
目指せ全国優勝
（部員）ハァあのさ
前から思てたけど―
Hey, I've been thinking this for a while,
but why don't we aim for something more attainable?
もう少し
達成可能な目標にしねえ
What?
They say that aiming for goals that are too
high is connected to losing confidence.
高すぎる目標は
自信喪失につながて―
よくないて言うじゃん
（田代）くう
Wh-What the hell?
な何だよ
Every time I would mention winning at nationals,
you would just scoff and ignore me.
（田代）今まで俺が
全国優勝言うたびに―
苦笑いスルしてたくせに
Now you want to argue with me?!
とうとう反論しやがて
What the hell?!
何だよ何かうれしいの
何でだよチクショ
Why the hell does this make me happy, damn it?!
はあ知るか
Huh?! Why would I know?!
目標を共有できた
気がしないが―
I don't feel like we really shared the same goals before,
but things seem to be a lot better now!
今の俺たちは
前より絶対いい感じだ
それに目の前の試合に
勝ちたいのは―
And we all share the desire to win the upcoming match!
揺るがず同じ
We're gonna win this thing!
絶対勝つぞ
Yeah!
（部員たち）おお
（澤村･東峰･菅原）わあ
And so, in the Miyagi qualifiers for the interhigh...
（澤村）そしてインタハイ
宮城県予選
（試合終了の合図）
Karasuno
Araigawa
Karasuno lost in the second round,
（澤村）烏野は
２回戦で敗退
and the third-years retired.
３年生は引退した
（横山(よこやま)静康(しずやす)）
ハァ地に落ちたな烏野も
The crows have had their wings clipped.
（澤村）くう
We started working together way too late.
（田代）俺たちは
団結するのが遅すぎたな
You know how they say,
"Chance favors the prepared mind," right?
“チャンスは―”
“準備された心に降り立つ”
て言うだろ
There's a chance that Karasuno may never get better.
この先烏野が強くなることなんて
ないのかもしれない
And even if they do, it could be years from now.
なても何年も
先のことかもしれない
それでもチャンスが来たら
つかめよ
Still, if the chance appears, you'd better grab it!
Now.
（澤村）今だ今いくんだ
We have to go now.
This is that chance!
これがチャンスなんだ
（ホイスル）
They clearly didn't prepare for Hinata's block,
so it'll definitely shake them up.
（鳥養(うかい)繋心(けいしん)）ここまでそれほど
警戒されていなかた―
日向(ひなた)のブロクが―
必ず相手を揺さぶている
（日向(ひなた)翔陽(しょうよう)）ふ
（繋心）それ自体はささやかな
亀裂であても―
That itself is a subtle crack,
and the wind's definitely blowing in our favor right now.
追い風は
確実に吹いている
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
（澤村）でや
Here's a chance to score!
(れおん)）チャンスボルとう
（嶋田(しまだ)誠(まこと)）クソ
Damn it!
Don't give up the tiny lead you've fought so hard for!
（滝ノ上(たきのうえ)祐輔(ゆうすけ)）やと奪た
半歩のリド死守してくれ
（白布(しらぶ)賢二郎(けんじろう)）五色(ごしき)
Goshiki!
Damn it! I started moving just an instant late!
（日向）ああ一瞬出遅れた
There's no way they can just ignore Hinata's
style of blocking where he suddenly pops up!
（影山(かげやま)飛雄(とびお)）日向の突然視界に
入てくるブロク
意識せずにはいられないだろ
It's definitely going to be a straight spike!
絶対ストレト
（五色(ごしき)工(つとむ)）く
（西谷(にしのや)夕(ゆう)）ぐ任せろ
Leave it to me!
（日向）えい
（東峰）でい
（ホイスル）
All right!
（繋心）うしゃ
（武田(たけだ)一鉄(いてつ)）ハァ
Nice spike, Asahi!
（澤村）旭ナイスキ
I can't lose to Hinata and Tanaka.
（東峰）日向田中(たなか)に
負けてらんねえからな
Kageyama, you made a great receive too.
影山もナイスレシブ
Thanks.
（影山）うす
（川西(かわにし)太一(たいち)）だ
（ホイスル）
Karasuno                  Shiratorizawa
（ブザ
His serve is powerful!
サブ強烈だぞ１本で切る
We have to stop him here!
Right!
（西谷･東峰）おう
（ホイスル）
（瀬見(せみ)英太(えいた)）く
Nishinoya!
（澤村）西谷
（西谷）すまん長い
Sorry! It's long!
（影山）う
Hold it, Tsutomu!
（五色）待て工
烏野セタは今後衛
Karasuno's setter is in the back row right now.
He can't do a setter dump. Watch carefully...
ツアタクはない見極め
（影山）ぐ
He's already there!
（五色）もういる
（日向）でい
（ホイスル）
All right!
（烏野一同）うしゃ
Damn it!
（ブザ
They're still as sharp as ever even this far into the match.
（天童(てんどう)覚(さとり)）ここに来ても
動きキレキレ
They must be stamina monsters.
スタミナ妖怪だな
Man.
（嶋田）いやあでも
あの動きを繰り返すのは―
That move's gotta be hard to repeat.
いくら何でもしんどすぎるだろ
Shiratorizawa!
We're counting on you!
（西谷）頼むぞ
Shiratorizawa!
（女子生徒）ああ
やとあの10番下がた
Number ten finally moved to the back row.
Shiratorizawa!
Tsukki! Don't lose to Hinata!
（山口(やまぐち)忠(ただし)）
ツキ日向に負けるな
Shiratorizawa!
What?!
（月島(つきしま)蛍(けい)）はあ
Shiratorizawa!
It's not like we're competing.
別に張り合てないし
Shiratorizawa!
（ブザ
Hey.
（月島）ちょと
（影山）ああ
Huh?
We're counting on you!
（日向）頼むぞ
（山口）おう
Right!
Shiratorizawa!
俺はできる
てめえはできんのかよ
I can do my part, but can you?
Shiratorizawa!
Well, I practiced with Akaashi, so...
まあ赤葦(あかあし)さんとちょとね
（影山）なこいつ
梟谷(ふくろうだに)のセタと練習してんのかよ
He's practicing with Fukurodani's setter?!
I'm super jealous!
クソうらやましい
（繋心）日向
（日向）あ
Hinata!
Sit down.
Shiratorizawa!
座れこからはスタミナ勝負だ
The rest of this match is going to be a battle of stamina. Rest while you can!
ちょとでも休め
（日向）はい
Shiratorizawa!
Yes, sir.
I don't want to lose to Hinata, either.
（山口）俺だて
日向に負けたくない
This time, I'm definitely going to create my own chance!
今度こそ
チャンスを作てみせる
（谷地(やち)仁花(ひとか)）山口君ナイサ
Give us a good serve, Yamaguchi!
Huh?
（田中(たなか)冴子(さえこ)）あれ今回はずいぶん
端こから打つんだね
Looks like he's going to hit really close to the edge this time.
（ホイスル）
Your serve will become a weapon.
（繋心）お前のサブは
武器になる
Just concentrate on hitting it straight.
ますぐだとりあえず
ますぐ打て
ウシワカのいるほうへ
Right to where Ushiwaka is!
（大平）うう
Yes! We broke through!
（繋心）よし崩したさらに
And...
Goshiki!
（牛島(うしじま)若利(わかとし)）五色
（五色）はい
Right!
（繋心）ウシワカがフォロ
Ushiwaka will have to set!
Three blockers!
（山形(やまがた)隼人(はやと)）ブロク３枚
Don't underestimate me.
（五色）ナメるなぶち抜く
I'm going to break through!
（月島･澤村）ワンチ
I hit it!
（田中）こんにゃろ
Get back here!
（山口）ナイスカバ
Nice save!
（天童･川西）あ
（天童･川西）１人時間差
A delayed timing attack.
（ホイスル）
（３人）おお
（日向）ほほおお
You're not the only one
（月島）合宿で新技
仕込んできたのは―
who was preparing a new move
at the training camp, Hinata.
君だけじゃないんだよ日向
All right!
（烏野一同）しゃ
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
Karasuno scored back-to-back points!
（男性）烏野ブレイク
That first-year is pretty ballsy.
（男性）あの１年
肝据わてんなあ
（ブザ
（ホイスル）
チクショ月島チクショ
Damn it, Tsukishima! Damn it...
Nice spike, Tsukki!
You're lowering your elbows!
（鷲匠(わしじょう)鍛治(たんじ)）全体的に
ひじが下がてきてる
You'll even miss the easy stuff like that!
ぶち抜けるもんも
ぶち抜けねえだろうが
You've got those huge bodies of yours!
でけえずうたい
してんだから―
So you need to be more, like...
もとこうこうやて
あのてあの
Dynamic?
（斉藤(さいとう)明(あきら)）ダイナミクに
（鷲匠）そう
Yeah, that!
ふむ確かに烏野の守備は―
Shiratorizawa!
It's true that Karasuno's defense
has been evolving during this match,
試合中に進化している
Shiratorizawa!
even if it's just a thin veneer.
たとえ付け焼き刃であてもな
Shiratorizawa!
But...
（牛島）
穴のない守備など存在しない
There is no such thing as a defense with no openings.
Shiratorizawa!
（ブザ
Do it again, Yamaguchi!
（田中）山口もう１本
（ホイスル）
（白布）ネトイン前
It's over! Up front!
Got it!
（山形）あいよぐ
（白布）う
（牛島）せい
Damn it.
（ホイスル）
Ushiwaka's spikes aren't easing up.
ウシワカ打点下がんねえなあ
But since he's spiked so many times,
he must be feeling it in his legs by now.
（月島(つきしま)明光(あきてる)）でも相当
本数打てますし―
そろそろ足にもきてるでしょう
Yeah.
ああ粘ていれば―
If he keeps going like this,
he'll eventually reach the end of his reserves.
ウシワカにだて
スタミナの限界は必ず来る
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
Go, Asahi!
いけ旭さん
（東峰）う
Got it!
（西谷）オライ
（月島）ぐ
Their timing was off!
（繋心･日向）合わない
（月島）ええい
（山形）く
（ホイスル）
Wow, talk about lucky!
よしラキ
うう心臓ヒュウてなた
My heart tightened like crazy!
But it all worked out in the end!
でも結果オライ
They're at set point!
セトポイントだな
（冴子･谷地）あ
（嶋田）
初めての５セトマチ
It's their first best-of-five match, and their opponents have been to nationals more than once.
相手は全国常連チム
The fourth and fifth set are
unknown territory for Karasuno.
（滝ノ上）４セト目以降は―
烏野にとてすでに未知の領域
He's able to make sense of
number ten's ridiculous attacks,
あの10番のむちゃくちゃな
動きの攻撃を成立させ―
and he's been doing it
the whole time like it's nothing.
試合開始から
当然のように維持し―
Precision is probably expected of him more than anyone else.
たぶん誰よりも
精密さを求められ―
誰よりも敵ブロカの
プレシャを受けながら―
And since he faces more pressure from
the opponent's blockers than anyone else,
he touches the ball more than anyone else playing.
試合中誰よりも多く
ボルに触る
Looks like that guy might've reached his limit first.
先に限界が来たのは
あちかもね
Sorry.
（影山）悪い
It's creepy when you apologize, so could you not?
謝るとか気持ち悪いから
やめてくんない
What?!
See? You're fine.
元気じゃん
（影山）フン
（月島）ハァ
（ホイスル）
（田中）大地さんナイサ
（澤村）ふん
Give us a good serve, Daichi!
（山形）前
（大平）うう
Up front!
牛島さん
Ushijima!
（ホイスル）
All right!
Damn it.
クソが
（ブザ
もしかして―
Could that be their second pinch server?
２人目の
ピンチサバでしょうか
Since it's Shiratorizawa, I'm sure they've got a deep bench.
白鳥沢(しらとりざわ)だから
選手層は厚いだろうな
Please just don't bring this to a deuce.
頼むからデュスには
持ち込ませるなよ
Let's go!
（湯野浜(ゆのはま)）いくぞ
（繋心）ジャンプフロタか
A jump float serve!
すまん
Sorry!
Azumane!
（影山）東峰さん
（東峰）ふ
拾た
（繋心）ウシワカだ
He dug it out!
Watch Ushiwaka!
若利
Wakatoshi!
Here we go.
いきますせの
Ready, and... jump!
クソが
（澤村）くう
Shit!
When you defend a part of the court,
（鷲匠）
コトのどこかを守る時―
you have to sacrifice another part of the court.
必ず他のどこかを
犠牲にしている
If you brace for a powerful hit and move back,
強打に備え後ろに下がれば
当然―
then the front will be open.
前が空く
（ホイスル）
Nice spike, Ushijima!
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
Ushijima!
（山口）ああ
They were totally aiming for the open space...
狙われた空いてるスペスを
Shiratorizawa!
I thought Kageyama would still be able to get that.
それでも影山は―
今のは取れたと思たんだが
Shiratorizawa!
He must be exhausted.
やぱり疲労が
Shiratorizawa!
バテバテセタ君には―
Is the exhausted setter going to
have to face the deuce of despair?
Shiratorizawa!
絶望のデュスかなルン
（影山）ああ
The only time I'll ever feel despair
俺が何かに
絶望するとしたら―
is when I won't be able to play volleyball anymore.
バレが
できなくなた時だけだ
Shiratorizawa!
All of you guys are monsters.
どいつもこいつも―
妖怪みてえ
Shiratorizawa!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
（応援団）さあいきましょう
（応援団員）さあいきましょう
All right, here we go!
守備の位置は今のでいい
The positioning of the defense is fine as-is.
You're able to follow up on partial blocks.
ワンチフォロできてるぞ
（部員たち）うす
Yes, sir!
影山はいけるか
Can you go on, Kageyama?
Of course.
もちろんです
If you're exhausted, I can switch with you whenever!
へばたらいつでも
代わてやるからな
I won't get exhausted!
へばりません
（ブザ
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
（ホイスル）
（湯野浜）ふ
（西谷）大地さん
Daichi!
It's not dropping.
（澤村）伸びる
（澤村）う
（影山）ふ
（東峰）ふ
（ホイスル）
All right!
（男性）よし
Yes!
Now they're at set point again.
これでまたセトポイント
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
（ホイスル）
（女子部員）ああまたデュス
It's a deuce again.
It's fine! They'll be able to...
（道宮(みちみや)結(ゆい)）
大丈夫取り返しあ
Ugh!
ああもう何でこのタイミング
Talk about bad timing.
（ホイスル）
（３人）さ来い
Bring it!
（影山）う
（澤村･西谷）あ
（澤村･西谷）く
（ホイスル）
Wakatoshi, the miracle boy!
ミラクルボイ若利
I can't believe that just happened.
ここでネトインなんて
ありかよ
Now Shiratorizawa is at match point.
向こうのマチポイント
（冴子）あと１点
取られたら終わり
If they score again, it's all over.
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
（応援団）あと１点
あと１点あと１点
Be Courageous Warriors
One more point! One more point!
頑張れ頑張れ
You can do it... You can do it!
（ホイスル）
Nishinoya!
西谷
（西谷）ぐ
（西谷）クソ鬼サブ
Damn demon serve!
Here's our chance!
（山形）チャンスボル
ヤバい
Crap!
Goddammit!
クソたれ
（白布）う
（影山･月島）く
（ホイスル）
（女子部員･道宮）やた
Yes!
They stopped it!
They survived the match point!
マチポイントしのいだ
That's amazing!
すげえ
Hey, could you not just run into me?
ちょとムダに
ぶつかてこないでくれる
You're not Hinata.
日向じゃあるまいし
上に跳びなよ上に
Jump up. Up.
What?!
ああこんなもん
ぶつかたうちに入んねえんだよ
There's no way that'd be considered bumping into you!
鍛え方が足(た)んねえんだ
You just lack training!
おおお前ら
You two!
Seriously, give me a break!
マジ勘弁しろよ寿命縮むわ
I can feel my lifespan shortening!
Hmph. This ain't nothing.
フンこんな状況―
屁(へ)でもねえわ
（男性たち）あん
Says the guy who was panicking when
Shiratorizawa had a chance to score.
（男性）
白鳥沢のチャンスボルの時―
めちゃうろたえてたくせに
（横山）屁でもねえんだ
It ain't nothing.
Karasuno
Araigawa
This is nothing compared to when they stopped being
a powerhouse school and didn't gather any attention.
強豪としての記憶は新しいのに―
誰の目にも止まんねえ―
あの頃に比べればよ
I'm counting on you, Karasuno!
期待してるぞ烏野
Whoa, what?
（男子生徒）何何
Who's that?
（縁下(えんのした)力(ちから)）誰
N-No idea...
ささあ
（菅原）フ
（東峰）フ
That old fart's still coming to our matches?
（鳥養(うかい)一繋(いけい)）
まだ見に来てんのかあのオヤジ
I guess we can't let him down, then.
期待には応えないとな
行てこい
Get out there!
（影山）俺にとて最高に
やかいな相手は―
For me, the most annoying person
isn't an opposing blocker.
どんな敵ブロカより―
It's him.
こいつだな
All right!
しゃあ
We're going to win!
（教頭）絶対勝つぞ
Go, go, Karasuno! Push it, push it, Karasuno!
いけいけ烏野
押せ押せ烏野
Go, go, Karasuno! Push it, push it, Karasuno!
（応援団）いけいけ烏野
押せ押せ烏野
Hey, Tiredpants.
（日向）ヘイバテ山(やま)君
No matter how shitty your sets are, I can hit them!
おれはどんな下手くそな
トスでも打つぜ
My sets are never shitty.
俺は下手くそじゃねえ
Roger!
（日向）うす
（ブザ
If Sugawara is coming in as a pinch server right now,
ここで菅原をピンチサバで
入れるてことは―
that means Kageyama is going to
be the setter for the rest of this set.
このセト最後まで
影山セタでいくてことか
Well, nothing good would come of
suddenly switching them right now.
まあこんな崖ぷちで―
突然代えるメリトはないしな
（ホイスル）
（澤村）スガ１本ナイサ
Land a good serve, Suga!
前
（大平）く
Leon! Up front!
（白布）う
（天童）え
（菅原）く
Nice receive!
（澤村）ナイスレシブ
Your beautiful form...
（天童）美しいフォムが―
乱れてるよ
is falling apart!
（日向）ううあ
（菅原）アウト
It's out!
（ホイスル）
（日向）おお
（天童）チェ
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
Yes!
（烏野一同）
よしゃ
I think it'd be okay to rely on the left wing spiker
a bit more, but Kageyama sure is confident.
（明光）レフトに任せても
いい気もするけど―
どこまでも強気だな影山君
It's a silent plea.
無言のアピルだな
（明光･谷地）え
No matter how tired he is or how tense things get,
he doesn't plan on backing down on the attacks.
（一繋）
バテようが崖ぷちだろうが―
攻撃の手を緩めるつもりはない
He wants the opposing middle blocker to have to keep his guard up.
ミドルブロカも
警戒し続けろよてな
（ホイスル）
（五色）さあ来い
Bring it!
（ホイスル）
うまい
（冴子･谷地）ああ
That was good!
Up front!
（大平）前だ
（山形）う
チャンスボルう
Here's our chance to score!
（影山）あ
（影山･繋心）短い
It's short!
（一繋）
バレはボルを持てない競技
Volleyball is a sport where you can't hold the ball.
You need to always be touching it.
常にボルを触てろ
I don't care if you use your hand or foot.
手でも足でもいい
You need to control that moment as though the ball
そしてボルが体の一部で
あるかのように
were a part of your body.
一瞬を操れ
His body's moving right, yet he used his left hand.
（天童）
体は右へ流れながらの―
左手
（セト終了の合図）
Karasuno                    Shiratorizawa
（烏野一同）
よしゃ
All right!
（武田）ああ
（繋心）災い転じて何とやらだな
They're turning misfortune into fortune,
or something like that.
Do you idiots have glue on your feet?!
足に接着剤でも付いてんのか
この野郎
You could've gotten that ball!
拾えるボルだろうが
Wow...
すごい
They finally tied it up!
やた追いついた
Seriously?
（男子生徒）マジかよ
（田中）日向ナイス
よく反応したな
Nice one, Hinata!
That was a good reaction!
（日向）あざす
Thanks!
This is our ultimate opportunity.
（澤村）今こそが最高の好機
If the chance appears,
（田代）チャンスが来たら
つかめよ
you'd better grab it!
We can do this.
（澤村）いけるぞ
Let's go!
いくぞ
（影山）ハァ
（日向）ほ
（影山）うう
（日向）ほげ
Nice save.
ナイスカバ
If you think it's nice, at least say it with a nice face!
（日向）ナイスぽい顔しろよ
More importantly, Kageyama.
それより影山よう
（影山）ああ
We get to play one more set!
もう１セトやれるぞ
Yeah.
When we were first-years, for about six months, I internally called you "Hafing Mwe," Asahi.
（菅原）俺旭のこと
１年生の半年くらい―
心の中で“シャフス”て
呼んでた
見た目外人ぽいのもあたし
You even sorta looked like a foreigner.
Actually, you called me that quite a few times out loud too.
に出てたよ
次回「ハイキュ」
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
Episode Seven:
Obsession
"Obsession."